so let's look at what kinds of
structures and what do we have in the
hardware with the Rob so we still have
the instruction queue from which we
dispatch into the reservation stations
we still have the rat that can point to
a register file or to the renamed name
for the instruction until it wres to the
register file but rat entries that point
to not to register file in in normal
tomasulo algorithm would point to the
reservation stations now however we have
a new structure called the reorder
buffer Rob it has a T and tail pointer
and basically the instructions that are
currently in execution are between these
two pointers the head pointer is the
pointer to where are we going to put the
next instruction that issues the tail
pointer is where we are considering
instructions for commit and the rat
entries that are not pointing to the
register file are now pointing to the
Rob entries for the instructions uh that
are going to produce that value